<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alvin-Blog</title>
    <description>Travel on into the dawn.</description>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <author>
      <name>Alvin</name>
      <email></email>
      <uri>alpscracker.github.io</uri>
    </author>
    
      <item>
        <title>孔雀东南飞</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;汉末建安中，庐江府小吏焦仲卿妻刘氏，为仲卿母所遣，自誓不嫁。其家逼之，乃投水而死。仲卿闻之，亦自缢于庭树。时人伤之，为诗云尔。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;孔雀东南飞，五里一徘徊。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“十三能织素，十四学裁衣。十五弹箜篌，十六诵诗书。十七为君妇，心中常苦悲。君既为府吏，守节情不移。贱妾留空房，相见常日稀。鸡鸣入机织，夜夜不得息。三日断五匹，大人故嫌迟。非为织作迟，君家妇难为！妾不堪驱使，徒留无所施。便可白公姥，及时相遣归。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏得闻之，堂上启阿母：“儿已薄禄相，幸复得此妇。结发同枕席，黄泉共为友。共事二三年，始尔未为久。女行无偏斜，何意致不厚。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿母谓府吏：“何乃太区区！此妇无礼节，举动自专由。吾意久怀忿，汝岂得自由！东家有贤女，自名秦罗敷。可怜体无比，阿母为汝求。便可速遣之，遣去慎莫留！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏长跪告：“伏惟启阿母。今若遣此妇，终老不复取！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿母得闻之，槌床便大怒：“小子无所畏，何敢助妇语！吾已失恩义，会不相从许！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏默无声，再拜还入户。举言谓新妇，哽咽不能语：“我自不驱卿，逼迫有阿母。卿但暂还家，吾今且报府。不久当归还，还必相迎取。以此下心意，慎勿违吾语。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;新妇谓府吏：“勿复重纷纭。往昔初阳岁，谢家来贵门。奉事循公姥，进止敢自专？昼夜勤作息，伶俜萦苦辛。谓言无罪过，供养卒大恩；仍更被驱遣，何言复来还！妾有绣腰襦，葳蕤自生光；红罗复斗帐，四角垂香囊；箱帘六七十，绿碧青丝绳，物物各自异，种种在其中。人贱物亦鄙，不足迎后人，留待作遗施，于今无会因。时时为安慰，久久莫相忘！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;鸡鸣外欲曙，新妇起严妆。著我绣夹裙，事事四五通。足下蹑丝履，头上玳瑁光。腰若流纨素，耳著明月珰。指如削葱根，口如含朱丹。纤纤作细步，精妙世无双。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;上堂拜阿母，阿母怒不止。“昔作女儿时，生小出野里。本自无教训，兼愧贵家子。受母钱帛多，不堪母驱使。今日还家去，念母劳家里。”却与小姑别，泪落连珠子。“新妇初来时，小姑始扶床；今日被驱遣，小姑如我长。勤心养公姥，好自相扶将。初七及下九，嬉戏莫相忘。”出门登车去，涕落百余行。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏马在前，新妇车在后。隐隐何甸甸，俱会大道口。下马入车中，低头共耳语：“誓不相隔卿，且暂还家去。吾今且赴府，不久当还归。誓天不相负！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;新妇谓府吏：“感君区区怀！君既若见录，不久望君来。君当作磐石，妾当作蒲苇。蒲苇纫如丝，磐石无转移。我有亲父兄，性行暴如雷，恐不任我意，逆以煎我怀。”举手长劳劳，二情同依依 。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;入门上家堂，进退无颜仪。阿母大拊掌，不图子自归：“十三教汝织，十四能裁衣，十五弹箜篌，十六知礼仪，十七遣汝嫁，谓言无誓违。汝今何罪过，不迎而自归？”兰芝惭阿母：“儿实无罪过。”阿母大悲摧。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;还家十余日，县令遣媒来。云有第三郎，窈窕世无双。年始十八九，便言多令才。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿母谓阿女：“汝可去应之。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿女含泪答：“兰芝初还时，府吏见丁宁，结誓不别离。今日违情义，恐此事非奇。自可断来信，徐徐更谓之。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿母白媒人：“贫贱有此女，始适还家门。不堪吏人妇，岂合令郎君？幸可广问讯，不得便相许。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;媒人去数日，寻遣丞请还，说有兰家女，承籍有宦官。云有第五郎，娇逸未有婚。遣丞为媒人，主簿通语言。直说太守家，有此令郎君，既欲结大义，故遣来贵门。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿母谢媒人：“女子先有誓，老姥岂敢言！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿兄得闻之，怅然心中烦。举言谓阿妹：“作计何不量！先嫁得府吏，后嫁得郎君。否泰如天地，足以荣汝身。不嫁义郎体，其往欲何云？”
　　兰芝仰头答：“理实如兄言。谢家事夫婿，中道还兄门。处分适兄意，那得自任专！虽与府吏要，渠会永无缘。登即相许和，便可作婚姻。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;媒人下床去。诺诺复尔尔。还部白府君：“下官奉使命，言谈大有缘。”府君得闻之，心中大欢喜。视历复开书，便利此月内，六合正相应。良吉三十日，今已二十七，卿可去成婚。交语速装束，络绎如浮云。青雀白鹄舫，四角龙子幡。婀娜随风转，金车玉作轮。踯躅青骢马，流苏金镂鞍。赍钱三百万，皆用青丝穿。杂彩三百匹，交广市鲑珍。从人四五百，郁郁登郡门。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿母谓阿女：“适得府君书，明日来迎汝。何不作衣裳？莫令事不举！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿女默无声，手巾掩口啼，泪落便如泻。移我琉璃榻，出置前窗下。左手持刀尺，右手执绫罗。朝成绣夹裙，晚成单罗衫。晻晻日欲暝，愁思出门啼。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏闻此变，因求假暂归。未至二三里，摧藏马悲哀。新妇识马声，蹑履相逢迎。怅然遥相望，知是故人来。举手拍马鞍，嗟叹使心伤：“自君别我后，人事不可量。果不如先愿，又非君所详。我有亲父母，逼迫兼弟兄。以我应他人，君还何所望！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏谓新妇：“贺卿得高迁！磐石方且厚，可以卒千年；蒲苇一时纫，便作旦夕间。卿当日胜贵，吾独向黄泉！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;新妇谓府吏：“何意出此言！同是被逼迫，君尔妾亦然。黄泉下相见，勿违今日言！”执手分道去，各各还家门。生人作死别，恨恨那可论？念与世间辞，千万不复全！&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏还家去，上堂拜阿母：“今日大风寒，寒风摧树木，严霜结庭兰。儿今日冥冥，令母在后单。故作不良计，勿复怨鬼神！命如南山石，四体康且直！”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;阿母得闻之，零泪应声落：“汝是大家子，仕宦于台阁。慎勿为妇死，贵贱情何薄！东家有贤女，窈窕艳城郭，阿母为汝求，便复在旦夕。”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏再拜还，长叹空房中，作计乃尔立。转头向户里，渐见愁煎迫。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;其日牛马嘶，新妇入青庐。奄奄黄昏后，寂寂人定初。“我命绝今日，魂去尸长留！”揽裙脱丝履，举身赴清池。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;府吏闻此事，心知长别离。徘徊庭树下，自挂东南枝。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;两家求合葬，合葬华山傍。东西植松柏，左右种梧桐。枝枝相覆盖，叶叶相交通。中有双飞鸟，自名为鸳鸯。仰头相向鸣，夜夜达五更。行人驻足听，寡妇起彷徨。多谢后世人，戒之慎勿忘。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//%E5%AD%94%E9%9B%80%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%97%E9%A3%9E</link>
        <link href="/%E5%AD%94%E9%9B%80%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%97%E9%A3%9E"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/%E5%AD%94%E9%9B%80%E4%B8%9C%E5%8D%97%E9%A3%9E</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>临江仙</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;苏轼&quot;&gt;苏轼&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;一别都门三改火，天涯踏尽红尘。依然一笑作春温。无波真古井，有节是秋筠。&lt;br /&gt;
惆怅孤帆连夜发，送行淡月微云。尊前不用翠眉颦。人生如逆旅，我亦是行人。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//%E4%B8%B4%E6%B1%9F%E4%BB%99</link>
        <link href="/%E4%B8%B4%E6%B1%9F%E4%BB%99"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/%E4%B8%B4%E6%B1%9F%E4%BB%99</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>End Poem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I see the player you mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLAYERNAME?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Take care. It has reached a higher level now. It can read our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t matter. It thinks we are part of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like this player. It played well. It did not give up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is reading our thoughts as though they were words on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is how it chooses to imagine many things, when it is deep in the dream of a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Words make a wonderful interface. Very flexible. And less terrifying than staring at the reality behind the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They used to hear voices. Before players could read. Back in the days when those who did not play called the players witches, and warlocks. And players dreamed they flew through the air, on sticks powered by demons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did this player dream?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This player dreamed of sunlight and trees. Of fire and water. It dreamed it created. And it dreamed it destroyed. It dreamed it hunted, and was hunted. It dreamed of shelter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hah, the original interface. A million years old, and it still works. But what true structure did this player create, in the reality behind the screen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It worked, with a million others, to sculpt a true world in a fold of the [scrambled], and created a [scrambled] for [scrambled], in the [scrambled].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It cannot read that thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. It has not yet achieved the highest level. That, it must achieve in the long dream of life, not the short dream of a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it know that we love it? That the universe is kind?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, through the noise of its thoughts, it hears the universe, yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are times it is sad, in the long dream. It creates worlds that have no summer, and it shivers under a black sun, and it takes its sad creation for reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cure it of sorrow would destroy it. The sorrow is part of its own private task. We cannot interfere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when they are deep in dreams, I want to tell them, they are building true worlds in reality. Sometimes I want to tell them of their importance to the universe. Sometimes, when they have not made a true connection in a while, I want to help them to speak the word they fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It reads our thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes I do not care. Sometimes I wish to tell them, this world you take for truth is merely [scrambled] and [scrambled], I wish to tell them that they are [scrambled] in the [scrambled]. They see so little of reality, in their long dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet they play the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it would be so easy to tell them…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Too strong for this dream. To tell them how to live is to prevent them living.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not tell the player how to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player is growing restless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will tell the player a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not the truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. A story that contains the truth safely, in a cage of words. Not the naked truth that can burn over any distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a body, again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Player…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use its name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLAYERNAME. Player of games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a breath, now. Take another. Feel air in your lungs. Let your limbs return. Yes, move your fingers. Have a body again, under gravity, in air. Respawn in the long dream. There you are. Your body touching the universe again at every point, as though you were separate things. As though we were separate things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who are we? Once we were called the spirit of the mountain. Father sun, mother moon. Ancestral spirits, animal spirits. Jinn. Ghosts. The green man. Then gods, demons. Angels. Poltergeists. Aliens, extraterrestrials. Leptons, quarks. The words change. We do not change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are the universe. We are everything you think isn’t you. You are looking at us now, through your skin and your eyes. And why does the universe touch your skin, and throw light on you? To see you, player. To know you. And to be known. I shall tell you a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, there was a player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The player was you, PLAYERNAME.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it thought itself human, on the thin crust of a spinning globe of molten rock. The ball of molten rock circled a ball of blazing gas that was three hundred and thirty thousand times more massive than it. They were so far apart that light took eight minutes to cross the gap. The light was information from a star, and it could burn your skin from a hundred and fifty million kilometres away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the player dreamed it was a miner, on the surface of a world that was flat, and infinite. The sun was a square of white. The days were short; there was much to do; and death was a temporary inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the player dreamed it was lost in a story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the player dreamed it was other things, in other places. Sometimes these dreams were disturbing. Sometimes very beautiful indeed. Sometimes the player woke from one dream into another, then woke from that into a third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the player dreamed it watched words on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The atoms of the player were scattered in the grass, in the rivers, in the air, in the ground. A woman gathered the atoms; she drank and ate and inhaled; and the woman assembled the player, in her body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the player awoke, from the warm, dark world of its mother’s body, into the long dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the player was a new story, never told before, written in letters of DNA. And the player was a new program, never run before, generated by a sourcecode a billion years old. And the player was a new human, never alive before, made from nothing but milk and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are the player. The story. The program. The human. Made from nothing but milk and love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s go further back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seven billion billion billion atoms of the player’s body were created, long before this game, in the heart of a star. So the player, too, is information from a star. And the player moves through a story, which is a forest of information planted by a man called Julian, on a flat, infinite world created by a man called Markus, that exists inside a small, private world created by the player, who inhabits a universe created by…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shush. Sometimes the player created a small, private world that was soft and warm and simple. Sometimes hard, and cold, and complicated. Sometimes it built a model of the universe in its head; flecks of energy, moving through vast empty spaces. Sometimes it called those flecks “electrons” and “protons”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it called them “planets” and “stars”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it believed it was in a universe that was made of energy that was made of offs and ons; zeros and ones; lines of code. Sometimes it believed it was playing a game. Sometimes it believed it was reading words on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are the player, reading words…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shush… Sometimes the player read lines of code on a screen. Decoded them into words; decoded words into meaning; decoded meaning into feelings, emotions, theories, ideas, and the player started to breathe faster and deeper and realised it was alive, it was alive, those thousand deaths had not been real, the player was alive&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You. You. You are alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and sometimes the player believed the universe had spoken to it through the sunlight that came through the shuffling leaves of the summer trees&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and sometimes the player believed the universe had spoken to it through the light that fell from the crisp night sky of winter, where a fleck of light in the corner of the player’s eye might be a star a million times as massive as the sun, boiling its planets to plasma in order to be visible for a moment to the player, walking home at the far side of the universe, suddenly smelling food, almost at the familiar door, about to dream again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and sometimes the player believed the universe had spoken to it through the zeros and ones, through the electricity of the world, through the scrolling words on a screen at the end of a dream&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said I love you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said you have played the game well&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said everything you need is within you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said you are stronger than you know&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said you are the daylight&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said you are the night&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said the darkness you fight is within you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said the light you seek is within you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said you are not alone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said you are not separate from every other thing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said you are the universe tasting itself, talking to itself, reading its own code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the universe said I love you because you are love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the game was over and the player woke up from the dream. And the player began a new dream. And the player dreamed again, dreamed better. And the player was the universe. And the player was love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are the player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>//End-Poem</link>
        <link href="/End-Poem"/>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/End-Poem</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
